http://www.scoutlink.net/privacy

Skip to content Skip to content
Menu HomeConnectConnect NowIRC (Webchat)Chat nowAndroid appOther IRC clientsChannelsTeamSpeakMinecraftAboutMapTexture packsCommandsFAQsTwitterFacebookDiscourseGamesRules & SafetyRulesStaying safeJOTA-JOTIConnect NowActivity BadgeGuideAboutActivitiesJOTI RadioGamesAboutStructureCouncilAboutMeetingsElectionsRulesCoordinatorsOperatorsTeamsHelp & Training TeamMinecraft TeamTech TeamBrandingHistoryCampsIRC CampNew Year’s BashNorthAmOZANZHelpCommandsGuidesFAQsVolunteerContactScoutLink is commited to accommodating for the privacy and safety of its users. This privacy policy explains what data we collect and how we use any personal information we collect about you when you use any of ScoutLink’s online services. By using any of ScoutLink’s online services, you consent to sharing your data according to the terms of this policy. If you do not consent then you must stop using ScoutLink’s online services.What information do we collect about you?Upon connecting to any of ScoutLink’s online services, we automatically collect your IP address and, if available, your connection’s resolve host. If using the IRC network, this information is logged against your chosen nickname. Website usage information is collected using cookies and activity logs.We also allow you to voluntarily provide additional information via our registration systems. Some ScoutLink services require registration. All of these services will require you to provide your email address if you choose to register. Most ScoutLink services do not require registration.The full information that ScoutLink may collect about you, either voluntarily or automatically, includes:Your nameYour username, appropriate to the service that is being usedYour email addressYour IP address / resolve hostYour approximate geolocation by IPYour Scout/Guide GroupLogs of your chats in public channelsIn addition to the above, if you apply to volunteer with us through our Volunteer Hub at https://volunteer.scoutlink.net, you voluntarily provide the following information:Membership NumberNational Scouting OrganisationDate of BirthCountryAnswers to questions about the position you are applying to (these questions differ based on the position)How will we use the information we collect about you?We collect information in order to enable better security and performance of our services. IP addresses are stored to enable the processing of network-wide bans and the grant of additional privileges where needed. This information is also used for analytical purposes, which may be shared within ScoutLink in anonymised form.We may, if necessary, share any of the information that we collect with the World Organization of the Scout Movement (WOSM) or any of its affiliated organisations, such as National Scout Organizations (NSOs). This information is only shared in the interests of safety and security, such as when processing safeguarding reports. We may also share this information with relevant Internet Service Providers (ISPs) for use in abuse reports. We may also, when necessary or when obliged by law, share this information with law enforcement agencies. This information may be aggregated and/or anonymised or shared in full.Information you voluntarily provide via registration, such as your email address, may be used to contact you with service updates, volunteering opportunities, and network information. You may at any time opt-out of these communications by contacting help@scoutlink.net.In summary, we use your information:to maintain the security and safety of ScoutLink and its usersto improve the service that we provideto contact you periodicallyto process volunteering role applicationsAccess to your information and correctionYou have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please email techteam@scoutlink.net. We may charge a small fee for this service.We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate.Users under 13Users under the age of 13 are not permitted to use ScoutLink’s online services without parental consent. ScoutLink does not knowingly collect sensitive personal data of users under the age of 13 where parental consent has not been given. In cases wherein it is discovered that a user under 13 is making use of ScoutLink’s online services without parental consent, their connection to the service will be terminated. If you are under the age of 13 and do not have parental permission to use ScoutLink, do not use this site.Public activityActivity in the public areas of ScoutLink’s online services, such as posts in the Discourse forum or lines of text sent to public IRC channels, is regarded as being in the public domain. All users of the online service may record or log this activity. All users must be aware that their public activity is open to scrutiny and collection by third parties and other users as well as ScoutLink network staff for the purposes of logging and reporting.CookiesCookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity. For further information visit www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org.You can set your browser to not accept cookies, and the above websites tell you how to remove cookies from your browser. However in a few cases some of our website features may not function as a result.Other websitesOur website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies.Changes to our privacy policyWe keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 07 July 2019. Users of ScoutLink will be notified of changes made to this policy via ScoutLink Discourse. Historical changes can be seen at https://gitlab.com/scoutlink/gdpr-policies/blob/master/PrivacyPolicy.md.How to contact usPlease contact us at help@scoutlink.net if you have any questions about our privacy policy or the information we hold about you. Facebook
Twitter
Instagram
